Overseas today, the Vice President met with European allies to discuss the war in Ukraine
ahead of President Trump's summit with Putin.
Ukrainian President Vladimir Zelensky has rejected the idea that his country would seed land
to end the war with Russia.
ABC's Chuck Sivirstean has details.
Vice President JD Vance in the U.K. this weekend meeting with European allies as President
Trump prepares to meet with Russia's President Vladimir Putin, a U.S. official telling ABC
news the talks, produced significant progress toward President Trump's goal of bringing
an end to the war in Ukraine.
President Trump missing his own deadline to impose sanctions on Russia.
Instead agreeing to meet with Putin in Alaska on Friday, marking the Russian President's
first meeting with a major Western leader since Russia invaded Ukraine more than three
years ago.
Ukraine's President Zelensky will not be at that summit.
He held a flurry of calls with European leaders.
Zelensky warning, everyone can clearly see Putin's tactics.
He fears sanctions and is doing everything to bail on them.
He wants to gain territorial spoils for the second time already.
French President Macron saying the future of Ukraine cannot be decided without Ukrainians.
President Trump has suggested a peace deal would involve exchanging territory.
There will be some swapping of territories to the betterment of both.
According to the Wall Street Journal, Europe and Ukraine have presented their own peace
plan to top U.S. officials.
It stipulates that seeding any land must be backed by iron-clad security guarantees, including
potential NATO membership for Ukraine and rejects Russia's proposal to hand over Ukrainian
Hill parts of the Donetsk region.
And although Zelensky will not be at Friday's summit, President Trump says he remains open
to a trilateral summit with both Putin and Zelensky.
Chuck Siebertson, ABC News, New York.